Let's go!
Ready, go!
No abnormalities were detected in the engine.
Copy that.
No abnormalities were detected in the fuel system.
You're Lieutenant Shikishima, right?
I'm Tachibana, from the Tsukuba Naval Air Group's maintenance squadron.
Do you remember me?
Tachibana-san!
Of course! Thank you for your help during that time.
Yes.
Wow, you managed to land that low-quality aircraft
on this hole-filled runway.
As usual, your skills appear to be reliable.
Even though my results in mock ariel combat are good,
going into a real battle with no experience is different.
Lukcily, a malfunction in the aircraft gave you some extra time.
Actually...
No matter how hard I try, I can't find the
error you're talking about.
What are you saying?
Isn't it a good thing to have people like you?
Even if you obey an order like "go die,"
the outcome of this war is already clear.
- Give me a gun!
- Yes!
An enemy attack?
- I'm not sure.
- What is it?
Something big!
Is it a new weapon for the US military?
Taki!
Taki! It's on the coast!
Copy that!
Wahh!!
Taki! Taki-san!
What is this thing?
- It's Godzilla...
- It's what?
That's what the guy on the island said.
He said that on days like today, when the deep-sea
fish float to the surface, it means Godzilla is coming.
Go... Godzilla?
It's no good.
Let's get out of here!
Run!
Hey, hurry up!
Hurry! Run, quickly!
What is that thing?
We're not sure either.
Lieutenant Shikishima!
What is it?
Can you go over there and shoot it with a 20mm?
You're the only person who can shoot it.
We're all just from maintenance squadron.
But wouldn't it be bad if it just gets injured?
No living being can survive being hit by a 20mm!
Hurry up!
Before it gets within attack range!
Hurry, hurry!
Go!
Hurry!
What is he doing?
Now! Shoot!
It's coming this way!
What should we do, Tachibana-san?
Ammo!
Get some bullets!
Idiot! Don't shoot it!
Stop, you idiot! Stop!
Ah!
Get out! Get out! Get out!
Hurry and get out of there!
Tachibana-san!
Shoot!
Ah...
Tomita!
Ahh... Ah... Ah...
Ah...
I'll draw it to the front!
Shoot to kill!
Why are you guys like this?
Hey!
Everyone is dead!
They're dead!
Hey! It's because you didn't shoot it!
Damn you!
Hey!
Move.
Isn't that loose?
Yes.
Pay attention carefully.
It's going to be a pain if things keep dragging on.
Yes.
Kōichi-san, is that you?
Ōta-neesan!
Didn't you go on a suicide attack?
Eh? Is that not the case?
And you came back with a calm face?
Shame on you!
It's because of all the soldiers are cowards that things
are the way they are!
If you guys had stayed strong...
...my children wouldn't have died.
Do you know what happened to my parents?
Everyone died.
This area was surrounded by fire.
Your parents too...
Same fate as my children.
"Come back alive."
That's what you said, right?
You thief!
Move! Move, move!
Get her!
Move! Move!
Huh?
- Please!
- Eh?
Stop! Stop! Stop right there!
Stop right there!
Hey, that's her, that's her!
Eh...
Onii-san!
Finally.
It's your fault, onii-san.
I can't come pick up the baby when you're hanging in an area like that.
Have you been here watching this entire time?
I was getting impatient waiting for you to move, ok?
You're hungry, aren't you?
Why didn't you just leave this kid behind?
Hey!
There's no way I could leave her behind in that place!
Eh?
Eh...
Please don't follow me.
If you leave us here like this, both me and the child will die.
I don't know you!
Once you're done, you're going home, all right.
Scary, isn't he? Onii-san is heartless.
What happened to your husband?
Was he taken into the army?
Do I look like I have a husband?
Eh? Then whose kid is that?
- Who cares?
- That's not a good thing!
During the air raids...
...this child's dying okaa-san asked me to.
So then...
you're not related to that child?
So what?
Are you an idiot?
You're not in a position to take in a baby
like that and live peacefully!
Even you couldn't abandon it, could you, onii-san?
Hey!
Name?
"Akiko"
No, your name.
Noriko.
Why do you act like that?
If you're acting like you're a vagrant,
it means you're probably poor.
Are you telling me to become a whore?
Don't give me that look.
In this day and age, it can't be helped if you
don't have any other options.
What about your parents and siblings?
Your parents?
Yeah.
They both died in the air raid.
You and me are the same, aren't we, onii-san?
Eh?
Hey, hey! Wait...
You...
Hey!
What's with that?
With what?
Don't play dumb.
The parent and the child you picked up.
Who do you think you are, picking up people like that?
No. They just showed up and settled down without permission.
If you haven't kicked them out, then you picked them up.
Hypocrite...
I'm not dealing with this, sorry to bother you.
Ah...
The baby... is she breastfeeding it properly?
Ah, no...
She's not the child's mother.
What is that supposed to mean?
If things continue like this, she'll die of malnutrition.
Right?
Ah...
Picking up a child you're not capable of raising...
What on earth is that all about?
I'm sorry.
It's not for you to eat.
Adults can survive no matter what they eat.
Use this to make gruel for the child.
Ah, there goes my white rice...
It's annoying, seriously...
1946年３月
Ah, damn it!
I'm soaking wet!
Damn it...
Did you get a job?
I did find something, but...
Eh? What's the problem?
Ah...
The pay isn't bad either.
Check this out..
It seems that just the preperation money is ¥3000 alone!
That's awesome!
It has to be a scam.
Just the other day, all the rice that you brought in was stolen.
That's not the case with this.
What's different about it?
It has a stamp of approval from none other than
the Ministry of Demobilization.
There's a reason that it pays so well.
The reason?
During the war, both the US military and Imperial Navy
secretly laid down mines, right?
It's a job to clean that up.
But the pay is insanely good, because...
Well...
There's no guarantee that I'll come back alive, is there?
What are you talking about?!
You just made it back alive!
There's nothinng else we can do!
At this rate, the three of us are going to starve to death!
Even Akiko will die if it keeps going on like this...
I understand that, but...
If we have the money...
If we have the money, we can even buy powdered milk from America!
For that reason, I'd...
It's no good if you die!
It's okay.
Just becaus it's dangerous doesn't mean I'm going to die.
It's different from the suicide attacks of 10 deaths and no lives.
And besides, I'll be on a special ship so the
magnetic mines won't be able to detect us.
This is... the special ship?
Hey, you! Are you the one who's going to be our next gunner?
I'm Shikishima.
Are you a boat gunner?
I used to be a fighter pilot.
What? What's this guy for?
You're a former fighter pilot?
I don't want to be with this wreck of a military shōnen!
Were you disappointed?
That this is what the ship is like?
The US military and Japan's Imperial Navy laid down
around 60,000 mines along the coast.
Well, there are many different types, but the most
difficult ones are the US's magnetic mines.
If a ship made out of metal passed by, it would react and detonate.
Ah, so that's why...
Yep. He catches on quickly.
Our main responsibility is to clean up moored mines.
This wooden boat is the best solution to counter magnetic mines.
I'm Noda.
I developed weapons at the Navy Arsenal during the war.
This is Captain Akitsu and Mizushima-kun.
You can call this guy "The Kid" and that one "The Academic."
How do you feel about addressing me like that, chou-san?
And I'm not a kid anymore!
You're still only a beginner, so being called a kid is more than enough.
Yeah, yeah, I haven't gone to war anyway.
This is the special minesweeper Shinseimaru.
Paired up with the Kaishinmaru right next to it.
Mines are like balloons that rise from the ocean floor.
We attached cutters to the cables between the
2 ships to cut the mines' wires.
That will cause the mines to float to the surface.
So that using this...
it goes DADADADADA!
Watch us.
Wow, this one's quite difficult to hit.
Can I do it?
Are you sure?
Because it's shaking...
...you have to predict where the bullet will
land before firing, and...
Woah!
Good job!
It's the same as shooting down an enemy plane.
Except, well, I was never in an actual battle.
Eh?
You have no experience in practical combat?
That means Shikishima and I are pretty much the same.
Idiot. You're completely different.
You can't fly a plane, can you?
If I had gone to war, I would've been a great help!
Ah, if only it lasted a little bit longer...
Are you seriously saying that?
I'm sorry.
Idiot.
Ah! Stop it!
Shoot it! Run away!
Evacuate! Evacuate!
Ah!
Ah... ah... ahhhh!!
Are you okay?
A bad dream again?
Dr... dream.
I see...
It's a dream...
Or maybe...
...you're a dream.
What are you talking about? Are you okay?
This is Japan, right?
Isn't it? I'm actually back, right?
Right?
I came back, didn't I?
Stop it!
I understand...
I know.
Nice place you built here. It's worth all of the money you saved up.
Please help yourself.
Ah, this is, this is...
May I take one?
Eh? That's...
That would be a waste of film!
Ah, that smile!
Just like that, just like that...
Yes!
Thank you.
Hey, Academic, don't go falling in love with Nori-chan.
What are you talking about? Noriko-san is a married woman!
Please stop! I'm not his wife!
What does that mean?
She settled down here without my permission.
I just let her stay because there was nowhere else for her to go...
Then whose kid is this?
It's her stepchild, though they aren't blood-related.
She's an orphan that was entrusted to her during the air raids.
Eh?
Isn't that a touching story in this day and age?
No, I'm just not thinking ahead.
Otō-chan.
- Akiko.
- Yes?
I told you. I'm not your tō-chan.
Shikishima, isn't it a bad idea to say that?
It's really unhealthy.
Both of you were brought into a family by fate, so
you guys need to be prepared for it.
Make them happy!
Shut up!
I'm not interested in that kind of thing.
Why?
Welcome back. I also just returned myself.
What's with your appearance?
How does it look?
I started working as an office worker in Ginza.
Eh... no...
I've given you enough money though, right?
I was thinking that I finally wanted to become
independent from you.
At this rate, Kou-san, you'll never find a wife.
Did you know?
Ginza's also recovering very quickly.
Isn't this a bit soon?
I've been thinking about this for a while now.
Ah... what about Akiko?
What will Akiko do when you leave for work, Noriko-san?
Sumiko-san will take care of her when I'm at work.
Eh... ah...
Sumiko-san is very enthusiastic about it.
She said, "I've raised 3 children myself."
Well if that's the case, it's fine then.
Well then, I'm gonna go get Akiko.
It is estimated that these large aquatic creatures will reach the Kantō
region of Japan within a few weeks at the latest.
Supreme Commander Douglas McAurthur has regrettably announced that
due to the situation with the Soviet Union, military involvement is not possible.
At the same time, they requested Japan to
strengthen all of it's security agencies.
This...
Was it a giant shark?
A whale?
Sharks and whales can't do this type of damage.
A new Soviet weapon?
Does that look like weapon damage to you?
Then what are you saying?
I can only assume it was something large like a mountain.
Like what?
You're just acting arrogant even though you don't
understand any of it either.
I was being skeptical until I saw this.
Godzilla.
Please look at that!
Ah?
On the day Godzilla came to the island, deep-sea fish were floating to the top.
You saw that thing?
It was a monster that looked like a dinosaur that had survived.
The locals call him Godzilla.
Godzilla?
Foolishness.
Does that type of thing even exist?
You were half-asleep and probably saw an enemy tank-
You probably won't believe me, but that Godzilla wiped out
the entire garrison on Ōdo Island!
Wait a second...
I thought unit that got wiped out by the US military?
Ōdo Island was ignored by the US during Operation Jumping Stone.
During that time, it was an emergency landing site
for malfunctioning suicide attack planes.
So then, Shikishima...
Are you a former suicide attack pilot?
If this is the same Godzilla as the one from the island...
...it will have grown bigger and more powerful.
Please give me a moment...
Why were we called out here in the first place?
You're not saying we have to fight that type of thing, right?
On this type of ship?
That's the case.
Eh? That type of thing's impossible!
What are we supposed to do with this kind of petty ship against
an opponent the US military can't even take down?
They told us to stall it.
Stall?
The Takao is coming from Singapore.
Eh? Heavy Crusier Takao? That one?
It was awaiting scuttling, but it appears that
they decided to bring it back.
Isn't that awesome! The Takao!
I was ordered to buy time until the Takao arrives.
This ship is from America-san, right?
Can't they deal with it themselves?
Things are getting weirder between America
and the Soviet Union right now.
They can't carelessly take military action.
They prefer we handle these types of trivial matters.
Is this a trival matter?
The only weapons we have is a 13mm gun.
They said we could use recovered mines for that purpose.
Haha! So that's why they called us out here.
The most important weapons are "locally sourced."
And regarding this, you are not allowed to tell anyone about it.
There it is. The usual gag order.
This country never changes!
Can it even change?
Let's swap places.
Ah, thank you.
You're too stuck in your seat, Shiki-san.
To think that the other opponent could be Godzilla...
I know how you feel.
When I think back to the war, sometimes I also have trouble sleeping.
I want to defeat the enemy.
But at the same time, I find it incredibly frightening.
There are only 2 of those, including a spare.
What's wrong?
The amount of fish on Ōdo Island is nothing compared to
what's happening right now...
Stay on gaurd! Stay on gaurd!
Godzilla is coming!
Stay on gaurd!
Here he comes!
Kid, keep your mines read to drop them whenever you want.
- Yes!
- Shikishima, prepare the machine guns.
Let's run away! We can't fight it on a ship like this!
There's still time!
Let's see how that works out, chou-san!
Academic, keep your eyes peeled and report back to me.
Chou-san!
Shinseimaru to Kaishinmaru!
It looks like he's about to make an appearance. Get ready!
We're taking all the credit for defeating the monster.
- Those bastards!
- Captain!
If we run away now, the Takao won't make it in time,
so where will the monster head for?
I don't want to see Tōkyō engulfed in flames again.
But this ship is no match for it.
Chou-san, I thought you hated government orders, right?
Ah, I do hate them!
However...
Someone has to draw the short straw.
This is just impossible.
Academic, engine!
Working on it now!
Shikishima!
Hurry up! Hurry over here!
Captain!
Got it!
Increase the throttle!
All right!
Drop the mines!
He's almost here! It's too late!
Even so, we still have to do something!
Now, kid!
Here it goes!!
Ahh!!
Did it do it?
It's not working!
Oh crap, oh crap, oh crap, oh crap, oh crap, oh crap!
Shikishima! Machine gun!
Yes!
Shikishima!
Ah... ah...
No good! It's useless!
Inside it's mouth! How about inside it's mouth!
Reel it in, reel it in!
Reel, reel, reel, reel!
Drop it!
Mizushima, ignition!
Yes!
Eh?
No way...
No way!
Ah?!
Get down!
Ahh!!
Did we kill it?
No!
Ah... ah... ahh...
The Takao!
Ahh, just in time.
Crap...
Can you shoot it again?
Did they do it?
What's that?
Ah...
Have you finally woken up?
Where am I?
This is the Yokosuka Hospital.
You were immediately transported here after words.
Ah... What about the people abord the Kaishinmaru and Takao?
Godzilla...
I see. Where did it go?
It's whereabouts are unknown.
Godzilla was heading towards Tōkyō.
If we don't hurry and issue the evacuation orders,
something bad will happen.
The government will be hiding this information from the public.
Why aren't they letting everyone know immediately?
Likely due to the fear of causing confusion.
Now isn't the time to say things like that!
If we don't evacuate, terrible things will happen...
Nobody wants to be held responsible for the chaos
that will inevitably be caused.
Information control is this country's specialty.
What on earth happened?
It has nothing to do with you, Noriko-san.
What's bothering you so much, Shikishima-san?
With your help, we've been living together to this day.
And yet I have no part of your life whatsoever?
If you're carrying a burden, I'd like you to share it with me.
I'm...
...one of the suicide attackers...
...who ran away.
Eh?
On the day of the attack, I pretended that
my plane was malfunction and landed...
...at a landing site on Ōdo Island.
These...
belonged to the maintenance crew there.
All of them died.
On that night, a giant dinosaur-like monster appeared.
They asked me to shoot it down with the machine gun
from a Fighter Zero.
But I...
I ran away again.
As a result, all of them were killed by the monster.
They all have should been able to see their families!
The monster was called "Godzilla."
And it appeared again.
But...
Once again, I couldn't do anything.
I'm really a person who doesn't deserve
to be alive!
Kou-san...
Survivors are supposed to live proper lives.
What do you understand, Noriko-san?!
I understand!
My parents said "Live!" to me as they were being
burned inside of the fire.
So because of that, no matter what, I cannot die!
That's what I've been feeling.
It's impossible.
Every night, every night, I have dreams about them!
"Come up here quickly," they say.
"How are you living your life so proudly?"
Those are dreams; just illusions created by you, Kou-san.
First of all... first of all...
Am I even alive?
I died on that island a long time ago...
Decaying...
Noriko-san and Akiko are looking at the corpse...
That's definently! it!
You are alive!
Kou-san is alive!
Don't you understand?
Yes, hold the spoon.
Yes, gently, gently.
Wait, wait...
Hm?
Yes, now stir the miso soup.
Yep.
Good, good.
Yes, we did it!
Yep!
Raddish. Akiko's favorite raddish.
Raddish.
Please give it a taste.
Yes.
Yes, please.
Drink the soup...
Yes, the raddish.
Delicious.
Hot? Is it hot?
Yep!
Hey, aren't the raddishes delicious?
Yep, delicious!
More!
Is it okay if we end this?
I'd like to live again.
Is this an example of...
Hurry up and report it!
Hurry!
Yes!
A costal defense ship from offshore partrol has reported
a giant creature heading towards Tōkyō bay!
So, it'll be here soon, won't it?
What's up?
Is this even possible?
Is it here?
Is this really a living thing?
Tōkyō Bay Defense Line, should we blow up the 4th district
to stop the unidentified creature from intruding?
Just a little bit more.
It will soon enter the 4th district!
Now!
Detonate it!
Did we do it?
No good.
It didn't seem to work.
The blockade of Tōkyō Bay is a failure! The monster
is now heading towards Shinagawa
It's extremely big!
Tha- thanks.
Breaking news, breaking news!
A giant creature in the Tōkyō Bay is heading towards Ginza.
If you are in Ginza, please follow instructions from
the police and begin evacuating immediately.
This is real.
Ginza...
Are you injured? Are you okay? Over here!
Ah...
Hey, what is that?
- What happened?
- What's up?
That's...
...Godzilla?
Woah!
Ah...
Ah... Ah... Ah...
Ahh...
Ah... Ah...
An unbelievable sight is unfolding!
An incredibly large creature is rampaging
through Ginza!
The Nichigeki is beying destroyed right now.
All those memories and plays, the Nichigeki...
that Nippon Gekijō is now crumbling before our eyes!
Ah, what a thing to say!
The town of Ginza, which survived the air rads
from the last war,
is now reduced to a pile of rubble!
Ah, what? The monster is approaching this
direction.
Right now, the face of a giant monster is passing before
our very eyes.
It has become very dangerous here as well.
Woah!
Hurry and run away!
You're in the way!
Stand up!
- Kou-san!
- It's no good if you die, hurry!
- Oh!
- We did it!
- Ahhh...
- Ah?
This is...
...the same as that time.
Noriko?
No... Nori... ko...
Ah..
Ah... Ahh.. Ahh..
Ahh... Ahh...
Ah!
Ahhh!!
AHHHHHHHHH!!!
The damaged caused by the creature is estimated to be around
30,000 killed and injured and over 20,000 buildings destroyed.
Rescue efforts have been going on since the disaster.
It seems to be difficult to trace the creature due to
the possible risk of radiation.
In addition, around various places in Ginza,
what seems to be flesh from the giant creature has been found and
the police are working night and day to dispose of it.
The center of Ginza is sealed off.
What will Akiko do now that things have turned out
so badly?
Hm?
When we're in trouble, we help each other out.
Aki-chan.
Hey.
When your otō-chan isn't around, you like to
come over to your oba-chan's, right?
Where's okaa-chan?
Okaa-chan...
She's away on a trip for work,
so you'll be with your oba-chan for a while.
Hey, Aki-chan. Aki-chan!
Are you okay?
So you're not going to forgive me?
It's because...
I had a stupid dream.
Shiki-san...
A secret operation to defeat Godzilla is actually underway.
It's a very unsettling...
...civillian-led initiative but...
Would you like to participate in it?
Everyone here is...
Yes, formerly a marine.
You know a lot.
I'm Hotta, the former captain of the Yukikaze.
As you all know,
Right now, Tōkyō was attacked by a giant and
mysterious creature,
causing an unprecedented crisis.
However, we do not have a military to protect the
citizens of this country.
It was determined that military action from GHQ would be highly
unlikely due to the risk of provoking the Soviet forces on the continent.
This means that we must face that monster with
civillian power alone.
It is for that purpose that we have gathered you all here.
As a result of negotiations, they have promised to provide
4 destroyers that were going to be given to the allies, but they...
Are you...
...telling us that we have to go on a ship again?
I saw that in Ginza.
I can't beat that type of thing.
After all, disarmed ships
can't fight back properly!
Yeah! How are we supposed to fight?
Eh... well regarding those matters, please
allow me to explain to you.
Noda-san?
This time...
Sorry about that...
This time, the person who devised the plan...
...is me, former Navy technical officer Noda Kenji.
First of all,
Eh, according to the legend from Ōdo Island, this
monster is called Godzilla.
Godzilla takes almost no damage from normal firemarms.
I saw it right before my eyes...
It even got hit by the main gun of Heavy Cruiser
Takao, but...
...it quickly regenerated.
So in secret,
I came up with another solution.
First, I'm going to show you a simple experiment.
The water in here is salt water with the same
concentration as seawater.
This Godzilla-like wood has a weight attached to it
so that it just barely floats.
In this state, if we pumped freon gas through
the tube,
what will happen if it covers the piece of wood
with bubbles?
What will happen?
Whether or not bubbles comes out, it'll still float, right?
Yeah, that's obvious.
That's what you'd think, right?
It sunk! It sunk!
The bubbles from the the freon gas enclose the wood
and prevent it from coming in contact with the seawater.
My plan is that this time, we use this on Godzilla, the monster
that attacked Tōkyō, and sink him to the bottom of the sea.
Hey, the Acedemic is a surprisingly awesome guy, isn't he?
Yep!
As you know, Sagami Trench off of the coast is more than
1500 meters deep...
...boasting an exceptional depth for waters off the coast.
Our current plan is to attach a large number of freon
gas tanks to Godzilla,
and have them all foam at the same time, covering it
with a curtain of bubbles.
Within a short period of time, it will sink into
Sagami Trench and the pressure will kill it.
We'll kill Godzilla with the power of the ocean.
This is the outline of Operation Wadatsumi.
That thing came from the see.
It isn't bothered by the deep water pressure.
According to my calculations, after about 25 seconds,
1500 tons will be exerted per square meter.
Even creatures that can normally survive in the deep sea
cannot with stand these types of rapid pressure changes.
And...
Can you absolutely kill Godzilla?
There are so many things about Godzilla's ecology
that we don't know about...
So we can only create countermeasures against it
based on our predictions.
That's bullcrap, isn't it?
However, since artillery fire is ineffective, this
is the best solution.
Can you kill him? Or can you not?
I can't say for sure.
Shikishima
There is a possibility!
Shiki-san!
Listen until the end!
Now, for a detailed explanation,
We use 2 destroyers to wrap the cable around Godzilla.
The cable is already equipped with a large amount
of freon gas tanks.
As soon as it's wrapped around Godzilla, all of the gas
releases,
and Godzilla is pulled down 1500 meters into the deep sea.
However, if that doesn't work,
we have a backup plan.
Everyone, please look at the courtyard.
Deploy!
Oh!
Awesome! Awesome!
I'm Itagaki from Tōyō Baloon.
What you just saw is an inflatable floatationd device
inspired by the ones installed on former Naval aircraft.
This so-called floating bag gains buoyancy by having
Carbon Dioxide blow into the air sacs.
Now, this can bring Godzilla, who will have reached the bottom
of the ocean, all the way back up to the surface.
Even if it is able to withstand the high pressure,
I don't think it will be able to withstand the
massive decompression that will follow it.
Of course, I cannot say for sure that we will
defeat it.
But the only thing we can do now is what we can.
To all those who survived the war,
I am sorry to ask you to take on a life-threatening
mission again, but I want you to understand.
Now that neither the US nor Japanese government can
help us out,
we are the only ones who can shape the
future for this country.
It's impossible.
I have a family.
I just can't do it. That goes for most of
the people here.
Why are we the only ones drawing the
short straws?
I don't want this to be like the war.
Quiet down.
Everyone, I want you to listen carefully.
This is not an order.
Those with personal situations are free to leave.
We have no right to stop you from doing so.
This...
We're not going to die for sure, right?
Of course not!
Well, then it's much better than wartime!
Yeah, for sure!
Someone has to do it...
So I guess there's no other way, right?
Without us, the ships won't be able to move.
- That's right!
- I know, right!
All right! Let's do it!
- Let's do it!
- All right!
Everyone...
Thank you.
Let's do it!
But...
I still can't believe you're the one who
planned this type of operation.
I've encountered Godzilla in real life.
So, that's why they gave me the green light.
So they called us in for the same reason,
didn't they?
Do you think it'll return?
Due to just recently landing in Tōkyō,
you can see it as an addition to Godzilla's
territory.
Worst case scenario...
Godzilla appears again sometime within the
next 10 days.
That's early!
Apparently, they've placed lots of
radition-detecting buoys.
We can't soley rely on our eyes to detect it.
First off, if you set a trap for it,
you're expecting it to come up and say
"Hai, how old are you?"
That's it.
Hey, that's impossible.
Please don't make fun of me. I'm thinking about
it carefully.
There's an underwater loudspeaker that's used
for acoustic minesweeping.
Using that,
we'll play back the recorded of the sound of
Godzilla from his most recent appearance.
The sound of Godzilla?
Eh.
Godzilla will chase after another being because he will
feel that his territory is being invaded...
At least he should...
"Should?"
It's always "should."
And what is that levitation-floating-device-thing for
in the first place?
I don't feel like it's gonna work.
Well then, what are you saying I should do?
Yes, yes, how about we use a destroyer to pull it
back up?
Don't say stupid things. Godzilla is estimated to
weigh around 20,000 tons.
The thrust of only 2 destroyers just isn't enough.
Ah...
Well basically, your plan is full of holes.
If you're going to say those types of things, then
please provide an alternative plan.
Noda-san.
Do you have any connections to fighter jets somewhere?
Fighter jets?
In the unlikely even it does appear on land,
we can anger him with gunfire and lure it
back to Sagami Bay.
After they were disarmed, all of them were burned
down, the Japanese fighter jets.
Even if there were some left, it
breathes Heat Rays.
Guiding it with an aircraft would be a
very dangerous job.
I don't care if it's dangerous.
Fighter jets are much more mobile than ships anyways.
Are you aiming to get shot down on purpose?
Are you just desperate?
Are you drunk?!
You just want to avenge Nori-chan.
And you've got a problem with that, don't you?
Now that...
Why didn't you take Nori-chan as your wife before
all this happened?
You knew how she felt about it, didn't you?
I wanted to do that too!
So why?
My...
war hasn't ended.
There were fighter jets?
Yep, but it's a very special one...
It's the Shinden, a local fighter jet designed
near the end of the war.
Specially designed for hit-and-run bombing attacks.
The maximum speed is over 400 knots.
It has a canard design and is equipped with
four 30mm guns.
It's an innovative aircraft that boasts exceptionally
weaponary and incorporates many new inventions.
Apparently, only a few prototypes were ever
deployed in combat.
They were deployed here for the final battle on the mainland,
but were forgotten about in the confussion after the war...
Since it was left unattended for so long,
the aircraft often goes rattle-rattle.
I can't fly it like this...
That's the problem.
A good mechanic...
No, a person capable of reparing this aircraft is
what we need.
I have a person in mind.
Former Ōdo Island Mechanic Tachibana Sōsaku-san?
Yes.
Tachibana, Tachibana, Tachibana, Tachibana...
Ah, he currently doesn't have an address registered.
I see.
We get tons of requests to search for people
every day.
It'll take a while for us to find him.
I need to get in touch with him about some
very urgent matters!
You're in a difficult situation. Even if you say that...
Please! Just do it!
The survival of the country depends on it!
Even if that's true, I can't do what's not possible.
I'm sorry.
Well then...
Do you know which unit Tachibana belonged to before
he switched over to Ōdo Island?
I'm doing all that I can...
But I can't seem to get in touch with that Tachibana-san.
There are many other excellent former maintenance personnel.
Why don't you just try a different one?
Please give me a little more time.
Why are you so obsessed with that person?
There's no telling when Godzilla will return.
It's no good if it's not Tachibana!
He's gonna recieve my message soon.
Please!
Ta... Tachibana...
Tachibana-san! It's you, Tachibana-san, isn't it!
What's your intention with this?
Ah!
You're saying all the deaths on Ōdo Island were
my fault?
What's up with that?
Sorry...
I knew that if I said that, you'd get angry
and come over here.
You shameless person!
That thing that attacked Ginza...
was...
Godzilla from Ōdo Island.
Our fighter jets need to be upgraded...
...so that I can defeat it!
I really needed to meet up with you so that I
could ask you do do that.
That's why the bullcrap letters.
Please forgive me!
Do whatever you want.
There's no way I'm gonna give you a hand.
Tachibana-san! Please wait, Tachibana-san!
Please wait for a second! Tachibana-san!
There's something I'd like for you to do.
This is something that only you can do, Tachibana-san.
I once detonated a mine inside of Godzilla's mouth.
It was far more effective than the guns on the Takao.
He's weak to attacks from the inside. Do you understand?
You...
I'm going to take a fighter jet full of bombs and
fly it into that thing's mouth.
That will definently kill it!
A suicide attack?
Your war isn't over either.
Ah, so you fell down?
Ow!
It's swelling up again pretty badly.
It's a little embarrassing since I was drunk.
I don't really remember what happened.
Well, it's no wonder you were so excited after
finding Tachibana-san, who you were
very particular about wanting.
A canard aircraft?
I heard rumors about it, it actually was built?
Tachibana-san.
Everyone, thank you for coming!
Are you Tachibana-san?
Is this the legendary local fighter jet Shinden?
Yes. Can you fix it so we can fly it?
We'll try everything we can.
Thank you.
Thank you. Thank you.
What's wrong?
If the planner-sama makes a face like that,
it's bad for morale.
I proposed this, but...
I started to feel like it would be a miracle
if the operation succeeds.
Even so...
The miracle won't happen if you don't
do anything.
That's true, isn't it?
And look at their faces.
They aren't idiots.
They know well that this is a tough
operation that risks their lives.
Even so...
Everyone looks so happy.
Maybe this time, they can be helpful.
Be helpful...
We all survived the war.
That's why I said, "this time."
Hurry up!
Please make room.
1 hour ago, off of the East Coast of
Hacijō Island at 33°10'N 140°01'E,
It was reported that the installed Geiger counters
had detected a reaction.
And then here and here.
Godzilla's approaching.
At last.
Reverse-calculating from this speed,
Godzilla will arrive at the trench off the
coast of Sagami Bay at 1100 hours.
In order to confront it,
we will depart tomorrow morning at 0800 hours.
All right!
However...
Will the device be completed by then?
Please take us with you.
The 3 hours it takes to get to the site are precious.
As an engineer, I want it to be perfect.
But you might get caught up in the fight
with Godzilla.
We all came back from the war too.
Everyone, if possible,
please go home and spend time with your
families tonight.
Are you saying to be prepared?
If you think about it...
If you think about it, this country has wasted
too many lives.
Tanks with vulnerable armor...
Due to negligance of supplies, most battlefield
deaths are due to starvation or disease...
The fighter jets didn't even have basic
escape methods,
in the end being suicide attacks and gyokusai...
So this time...
I want to be proud of this civillian-led operation for
not having a single casualty.
This time, the battle is not a fight to the death.
It's a fight to live in the future.
All right... all right...
Let's do it!
All right! Let's do it!
It's finally happening tomorrow. I'm trembling
with excitement!
You're not coming with us.
What do you mean?
Well, those hands aren't going to do you any good.
Shikishima's going too, right?
Is it because I don't have any experience with war?
Do you really think I'm useless?
Kid, you're lucky that you didn't go to war.
I want to protect this country too!
Why can't I come with you?
We've been together for a while now!
Please!
Please take me with you too!
I want to go with you too!
I leave this country to you.
Captain!
Noda-san!
Lower it a bit... carefully...
See you, Aki-chan.
Ah...
Thank you for everything.
Akiko. Did you have fun at oba-chan's house?
It was fun.
I see. That's good.
Are you giving that to me?
Thanks.
Akiko.
Hmm?
Is this me, okaa-chan, and you, Akiko?
Okaa's in it, too.
I see.
You drew it well.
Why are you making that face?
What's wrong?
Akiko.
Hey, hey!
Hey, it's okay! I'm not going anywhere...
Tachibana san.
Can you deploy it?
I'll get it ready now.
The ordered bomb.
Two machine guns, 140 kilograms; 120 rounds,
80 kilograms, and...
One of the main fuel tanks, 400 kilograms,
were removed.
Instead, this plane was fitted with a No. 25 bomb in
the nose and a No. 50 bomb in the fuselage.
Now, I can finally repay my debt.
That's hilarious...
I feel like I want to live.
Those who died that day felt like that too.
Everyone wanted to come back alive.
But their wishes weren't granted. They were
killed like insects.
I understand.
The kid who drew this is named "Akiko."
I want you to protect her future.
I'll kill absolutely Godzilla, even if
it means I have to kill myself.
It seems like you finally made up your mind.
All right then, I'm gonna tell you something important.
Look.
This is the bomb's safety device.
Pull it out right before you plunge into him.
Okay?
And...
Aki-chan.
What's wrong? Are you lonely?
Here.
"To Sumiko-san"
Otō-chan...
Hmm? Otō-chan?
It's okay, it's okay.
This is Kuroshio 12, 35°03'N, 139°41'E.
A large amount of deep-sea fish emerging have
been spotted!
Godzilla spotted in Sagami Bay!
Currently, we are attempting to use an underwater
loudspeaker unit to guide it to the area of the operation.
Advance schedule for each ship!
Only take essential items with you!
Let's hurry up and board the ship!
Let's hurry!
Looks like Mizushima-kun gave up, didn't he?
I feel bad for him, but it can't be helped.
I actually don't want Shiki-san to
fly either.
Isn't Shiki-san a suicide attack survivor?
Seems impossible.
Akiko is here. He'll definently come back.
Underwater loudspeaker destroyed.
Godzilla has invaded Sagami Bay. Wadatsumi Squadron,
set sail immediately.
Hey!
Over there!!
It's here already?
Godzilla breaks through the final defense zone!
Landing is imminent!
I'm leaving!
With this, you're going to end it all.
Shikishima.
Depart from port immediately.
Repeat, all ships of the Wadatsumi Squadron
are to depart from port immediately.
What should we do? That plan's completely
falling apart!
Even so, we'll still set sail.
The missles must be dropped off of the coast of
Sagami Bay, where it will have the greatest effect.
We have no way but to rely on Shiki-san to
lure it.
Yes!
Let's do it!
Noda-san! It's from Shikishima-san!
This is Shikishima, takeoff was a success.
Now guiding Godzilla into the area of
the operation.
We'll be ready soon too.
So let's get to the operation area quickly...
Shikishima! Don't do anything crazy!
If you leave Akiko all alone, I'll
never forgive you!
Can you hear me, Shikishima?
Damn it, he's ignoring me...
Telegram!
Yes...
Yes?
Are you Shikishima-san?
It's a telegram.
Yes.
Woah!
Haha! That's a big deal!
Godzilla's quite pissed off.
It's in pursuit.
It's our turn, isn't it?
All ships, prepare for battle!
Freon cylinders, all right!
46cm shells, all right!
Floatation device switch, all right!
Concentration cables, all right!
All circuits connected!
Confirming power and releasing
the safety switch.
All right, nice!
Unit 1, attack as planned.
As planned!
Nice!
That's... Godzilla's Heat Ray.
It's impossible to do this type of thing!
Captain! I recommend that we immediately
evacutate the ship.
No. This is good.
Please start the operation immediately.
But when will Heat Ray come again?
As I told you,
Once the Heat Ray is used, it takes time
to regenerate it.
Now!
Please make up your mind!
Operation Wadatsumi begins!
Start to deploy the 46cm shells, cylinders,
and floatation device!
Shiki-san!
Crane deployed!
Copy that!
Send to Hibiki, maintain course.
Hibiki, maintain course.
I don't mind a little damage, we're going
to maintain this level of speed!
Hibiki approaching, 4 meters.
2 meters.
Brace for impact.
Brace for impact!
Cross complete! Full speed ahead!
Full speed ahead!
All right! All right!
Chou-san, switch!
Oh!
Crap! Already?
Almost...
Ready...
Chou-san, now!
- Cylinder!
- All right!
Depth: 1200.
1300.
1400.
Go!
1500.
Target depth reached!
Godzilla has gone silent!
Did we do it?
Stubborn bastard!
Moving to the backup plan.
Do it.
Come up here!
Depth: 1200.
1100, 1000!
The cables have stopped!
They stopped at a depth of 803!
Why? Why did they stop?
He chewed them all apart.
To Hibiki! We'll pull from all directions
to lift up Godzilla.
Full speed ahead at 90 degrees!
But the thrust of 2 ships isn't enough.
There's no other options!
Do everything you can!
Yes!
If this continues, the crane won't
be able to hold it anymore!
It's no good!
Ah...
This is the Yokohama Tugboat' company's
Fujimaru. We'll do our best to help out.
That voice...
It's Mizushima. Are you the captain?
Kid! It's you?
Yes!
This is Koeimaru, another ship from Tōyō Kisen.
We, the Nikkōmaru from the Yokohama
Tugboat Company, will cooperate.
Shiokazemaru will assist you.
- Tetsuyūmaru.
- Nanamimaru.
- Minamimaru.
きっしょうまる
- Junseimaru.
- Heimitsumaru.
- Tenyūmaru.
- Kaiōmaru.
- Yūga.
- Chōkamaru.
- Jūseimaru.
- Taramaru.
- Yasagamaru.
Please stop calling me "useless!"
All right!
You don't say.
I'm both surprised and impressed with him.
Get the tugboats!
All the ships will pull up Godzilla!
Get the tugboats
Get the tugboats!
The depth has started increasing!
Come up here, come up here!
Depth: 700.
Raise, raise, raise...
It's not damaged enough!
All ships take evasive action!
What's he going to do?
No way!
That can't be!
It's no good! Shikishima!
Shikishima...
No, that!
I see...
I see.
The crew member escaped safely.
This seat serves as an escape device.
Pull that lever to activate it.
Live.
Tachibana-san.
Shikishima!
You did it!
Kid!
Sumiko-san!
Kōichi-san!
Kōichi-san...
Akiko...
Eh?
Kou-san, is your war...
Over?
Yep.
Subtitles by themirrazz